Marcos Vinícius dos Santos

E-mail: contato.marcosvinicius25@gmail.com From: Garopaba - SC - Brazil

Github: @mrviniciux

Skills

- 5+ years of Javascript (ReactJS/NextJS) experience;
- Website optimization for search engines (SEO);
- Languages: English (4/5),
 Portuguese (5/5)

- Scrum methodology and kanban;
- GIT Github/Gitlab/Bitbucket;
- SQL and databases such: MySQL, Oracle, MariaDB.
- Root Cause Analysis;

Work experience

jul 2022 until aug 2024

Frontend|DevOps Engineer / Grupo SBF - São Paulo - SP - Brazil

- Large-scale and high-availability applications using kubernetes and defect dojo
- Scrum & Kanban
- NextJS + React + Context API + Typescript
- Google Cloud Platform (GCP)
- API consumption by BFF
- Collaboration with product designers to create a good UI/UX

mar 2021 until jul 2022

Frontend Developer / Codeminer42 - São Paulo - SP - Brazil

- Building solutions on frontend using React, Context API and Redux;
- First steps with Elixir and Phoenix Framework;
- Working for another company called Intellimize from California using frontend technologies like Vanilla Script and JQuery

Jun 2020 to mar 2021

Software developer / Mouts - Blumenau - SC - Brazil

- Development of solutions and recourses to Philips EMR Blumenau;
- Optimize and implement solution from eCM/ICCA Philips International to Tasy;
- Constant use of Tasy framework to implement schematics;
- Maintenance and implementation of source code in Java (Tomcat/Gradle), Javascript(AngularJS/Vanilla Script) and SQL(OracleDB).

May 2018 to may 2020

Frontend Developer / Velow - Blumenau - SC - Brazil

- Development of single page applications with javascript using Angularis and React; Having the Material design and AntDesign as default layout reference;
- Reports and charts with Jasper Reports with continuously integration on rails api;
- Technical analysis of solicitations together with the project PO;
- Configuration of Ubuntu and CentOS 7 distributions to run RVM and rails versions;
- Guild and monitor the frontend team composed of two people.

July 2017 to March 2018

Full Stack PHP Developer / RKAM Soluções - Gaspar - SC - Brazil

- Development of web applications using PHP together with: Slim, Silex and Codeigniter as frameworks;
- MySQL maintenance and query select;
- First experiences with AngularJS;
- Elaboration of technical and functional specifications.

July 2014 até July de 2017

Technical Support / Multitherm Sistemas e automação - Blumenau - SC - Brazil

- Firebird maintenance and guery select;
- Report development and customization (JasperReports and QuickReport);
- Maintenance and exportation of data to fiscal SPED;
- ERP configuration to send command to thermal printers and scales (HP);
- Solve problems and answer customers doubts on cellphone or remote access keeping the courtesy and agility. The main product of Multitherm is an ERP solution integrated with automation;
- First experiences with Ubuntu, Red Hat and Windows Server 2008 configuring: DHCP, Firewall, backup and schedules. Learned to use Linux terminal and Powershell.

Apprentice / Giassi - Blumenau - SC - Brazil

- Customer service;
- Basics of excel, word and powerpoint.

Education

Jan 2001 to Dec de 2002

Day-care and Pre-school / C.E.I Heinrich Heiff - Blumenau - SC - Brazil

Jan 2003 to Dec 2011

Pre-school, Elementary School and Middle School / E.B.M Gustavo Richard - Blumenau - SC - Brazil

Jan 2012 to Dec 2015

High School / E.E.B João Widemann - Blumenau - SC - Brazil

About

I started working at 14 years old. Despite not being able to work with technology at that time, due to lack of opportunities, my main goal was always to work with computers. At 16 I found a job as Technical Support and moved forward with web development (PHP + HTML + CSS + VanillaJS).

I Have some completed courses associated with frontend at Caelumn and actually I'm looking for more knowledge about functional backend and frontend like RxJS, Elixir, Erlang, Clojurescript.